我们看世界的方式实际上非常复杂。我们的眼睛不像相机那样
The way we see the world is actually quite complex. Our eyes are not like a camera that
拍摄我们然后去处理的图像。当我们看一个场景时，我们的眼睛不断移动
takes an image that we then go and process. As we look at a scene our eye moves continuously
在场景中的不同点，以提高其对内容的理解
to different points in the scene in order to improve its understanding of what is in
它的前面。所以看到实际上是一个非常活跃的过程。
front of it. So seeing is actually a very active process.
因此，研究人员开发出的技术可以让我们研究人类的位置
So researchers have developed technology that allows us to study where a human being is
看着;涉及一个摄像机，它可以看到被摄体的眼睛，也许还有一个照明
looking; involves a camera which looks at the subject’s eyes, and perhaps an illumination
系统。因此，通过这种方式，我们可以持续，实时地在人类正在寻找的地方进行锻炼。
system. So with this we can work out continuously and in real time where a human being is looking.
现在这幅画被用于一项非常着名的研究，该研究于1967年进行
Now this painting was used in a very famous study that was conducted back in 1967 into
人类主体的凝视如何取决于他们被问到的特定问题。
how a human subject’s gaze depends on the particular question that they were asked.
所以他们能做的就是拿一个主题，问他们一个问题，然后跟踪他们的位置
So what they could do is take a subject, ask them a question and then track where their
眼睛看着画里。所以这是一个例子：这是一个跟踪，一个主题
eye looked within the painting. So here is an example: here is one trace, one subject
跟踪。你可以看到他们的目光在房间里四处移动。在这三个问题中，
trace. You can see that their gaze is moving all around the room. So of these three questions,
您认为哪个问题导致了这种特殊的凝视模式
which question do you think was asked that led to this particular gaze pattern by that
人类主体。我会让你暂时考虑一下。
human subject. I will let you think about that for a moment.
这是答案。提出的问题是：'什么是物质情况
And here is the answer. The question that was asked is: ‘What are the material circumstances
这个家庭？'所以为了回答这个问题，人类
of the family?’. So in order to answer this question, the human
主体已经将目光投向了特定家庭的财产。所以他们是
subject has directed their gaze towards the possessions of the particular family. So they’re
检查家具，他们正在检查墙上的画作，等等。所以
checking out the furniture, they are checking out the paintings on the wall and so on. So
给一个主题一个特定的问题，我们的眼睛以特定的方式在场景中移动
given a specific question to a subject, our eye moves over the scene in a particular way
以便最好地回答这个问题。这不仅仅是拍照的问题
so as to best answer the question. It’s not just a matter of taking a picture and
处理它：我们的眼睛主动在场景中移动，以便最好地回答问题。
processing it: our eye actively moves around the scene in order to best answer the question.
这是另一个实验。看看你是否可以找出问题。
Here is another experiment. See if you can work out which question has been asked.
我们可以看到凝视特别是检查特定人的面部区域
We can see that the gaze is checking out particularly the facial regions of the particular people
这里。所以被问到的问题是：“这幅画中的人物年龄是多少？”。
here. So the question that was asked is: ‘What are the ages of the figures in the painting?’.
很明显，看一看人们的面孔是有用的，以便弄清楚他们的想法
So clearly it is useful to look at the faces of the people in order to work out what their
年龄是。第三，在这种特殊情况下，这是
age is. Third one, in this particular case this is
这个主题的凝视是做什么的。我们可以看到他检查面孔，它也是
what the subject’s gaze did. We can see him checking out the faces, and it is also
在这幅画中检查每个人类主体的整个身体。问题
checking out the whole body of each of the human subjects in this painting. And the question
有人问：“这个家庭穿什么类型的衣服？”。
that was asked is: ‘What type of clothes are the family wearing?’.
因此，如果主题回答了这个特定的问题，那么他们的目光只是集中注意力
So given the subject was answering that particular question, then their gaze is focused just
在每个人的脸和衣服上。它不是在看家具;
on the faces and the clothes of each of the people. It is not looking at the furniture;
它不是在看画作;它看不到窗外。
it is not looking at the paintings; it’s not looking out the window.
重要的是要了解视觉是一个非常活跃的过程。现在它被驱动了
It is important to understand that seeing is a very active process. Now it is driven
也许是人体内一些运动最快的肌肉。所以人眼能够
by perhaps some of the fastest moving muscles in the human body. So the human eye is able
以每秒高达六百度的速度旋转，并具有惊人的加速度，
to rotate at up to six hundred degrees per second, and has a phenomenal acceleration,
像每秒35000º的平方，所以惊人的肌肉能够指向眼睛
something like 35000º per second squared, so amazing muscles are able to point the eye
很快在眼睛视野范围内的任何地方。
very quickly anywhere within the field of view of the eyes.
因此，我非常喜欢这位非常有名的早期视觉研究员大卫
So this lovely quote that I like very much by a very famous early vision researcher David
马尔。他说视觉是“从图像中发现存在的东西的过程
Marr. And he says vision is ‘the process of discovering from images what is present
在世界和它的所在地。因此，愿景是一个过程。我认为这是非常重要的
in the world and where it is’. So vision is a process. I think that is a very important
当我们开始思考机器人可能会看到的时候，我们会把这个消息带走。
message to take away when we start to think about how robots might see.